Guide to the North Carolina State University, Department of Entomology Drawings and Papers
North Carolina State University, Department of Entomology Drawings and Papers
1926-2000
MC 00285
The North Carolina State University Entomology Department Drawings and Papers is principally a compilation of taxonomic illustrations of thousands of species of insects, 1967-1990. The illustrations are in a variety of media, mainly drawings and paintings, as well as photographs, negatives, and slides. They were produced by independent artists hired by the NCSU Entomology Department, members of the entomology faculty, and the United States Department of Agriculture. Most of the illustrations were executed for the Entomology Department in the 1970s by five primary artists. This collection also contains entomological publications, 1973-2000, primarily of the North Carolina Agricultural Extension Service (later Cooperative Extension Service), edited and authored by James R. Baker. These publications are mainly pest control manuals, as well as copies of a pest control informational serial. Also included is early professional correspondence of Baker regarding entomological publications and taxonomy, 1966-1975.
The illustrations in the North Carolina State University Entomology Drawings and Papers, depicting thousands of species of insects and their taxonomy, were created or collected by the NCSU Entomology Department from 1967 to 1990. James R. Baker (1941- ) was curator of the collection during his career as researcher and professor of entomology at the university from 1972 to 2000.
16 linear feet
North Carolina State University Libraries, Special Collections Research Center
This collection is open for research; access requires at least 48 hours advance notice. Copies of VHS tapes must be made prior to patron use.
Transferred by the North Carolina State University Department of Entomology, 2000.
This collection is divided into four series: Taxonomic Illustrations, Oversized Illustrations, James R. Baker Papers, Publications.
The illustrations in the North Carolina State University Entomology Drawings and Papers, depicting thousands of species of insects and their taxonomy, were created or collected by the NCSU Entomology Department from 1967 to 1990. Rendered through a variety of processes, they were produced by independent artists hired by the Entomology Department, members of the entomology faculty, and the United States Department of Agriculture. James R. Baker (1941- ) was curator of the collection during his career as researcher and professor of entomology at the university from 1972 to 2000. He received a B.S. (1966) and M.S. (1968) from N.C. State, and a Ph.D. from the University of Kansas (1972).
Most of the illustrations in the collection were executed for the Entomology Department in the 1970s by five artists: Ponglerd Kooaroon, Susan Van Gieson, James Wilcox, Lewis L. Deitz, and James Baker. The illustrations by Kooaroon, an architecture graduate student at North Carolina State, are drawings in Prismacolor pencil on coquille paper, in addition to paintings in acrylic. Van Gieson, a local artist, also painted in acrylic, and did renderings in pen and ink. Wilcox used radiograph pens and mastered the stippling technique in his illustrations. Both Baker and Deitz, another entomology faculty member, employed various drawing and painting techniques, Deitz particularly concentrating on radiography.
North Carolina State University Cooperative Extension Service, Publications, UA 102.200
North Carolina State University College of Agriculture and Life Sciences, Publications, UA 100.200
North Carolina State University College of Agriculture and Life Sciences, Department of Entomology Records, UA 100.017
The North Carolina State University Entomology DepartmentDrawings Drawings and Papers is principally a compilation of taxonomic illustrations of thousands of species of insects, 1967-1990. The illustrations are in a variety of media, mainly drawings and paintings (in pencil, pen and ink, pastel, and acrylic; on paper and plastic transparencies), as well as photographs, negatives, and slides. Most were produced in the 1970s by members of the entomology faculty and independent artists hired by the department.
This collection also contains entomological publications, 1926-2000, primarily of the North Carolina Agricultural Extension Service (later Cooperative Extension Service), edited and authored by James R. Baker, who was a researcher and professor of entomology at North Carolina State University from 1972 to 2000, and curator of the collection. These publications are mainly pest control manuals, as well as copies of a pest control informational serials. Also included is early professional correspondence of Baker regarding entomological publications and taxonomy, 1966-1975, and a videotape, 1988.
Baker James R. James Robert 1941-; North Carolina Cooperative Extension Service; North Carolina State University Department of Entomology; Publications; North Carolina Entomologists; Control Insect pests Handbooks, manuals, etc.; Classification Insects; North Carolina Study and teaching Entomology; Drawings; Scientific illustrations
- Taxonomic Illustrations, 1967-1990; 1967 1990; 8.517 archival boxes
  This series consists mainly of illustrations of insects in a variety of media, mainly drawings and paintings, as well as photographs, negatives, and slides, 1967-1990. The folders are arranged alphabetically, primarily by species common name. Also included with the illustrative material are printed materials and lecture notes. Taxonomic illustrations larger than legal size are contained in Series 2, Oversized Illustrations.
  - Alfalfa Weevil (Box 1, Folder 1)
  - Angoumois Grain Moth (Box 1, Folder 2)
  - Ants (Box 1, Folder 3)
  - Apple Aphid (Box 1, Folder 4)
  - Arborvitae Leaf Miner (Box 1, Folder 5)
  - Armored Scales (Box 1, Folder 6)
  - Army Cutworm (Box 1, Folder 7)
  - Armyworm (Box 1, Folder 8)
  - Asiatic Garden Beetle (Box 1, Folder 9)
  - Asparagus Aphid (Box 1, Folder 10)
  - Ataenius Spretulus (Box 1, Folder 11)
  - Azalea Bark Scale (Box 1, Folder 12)
  - Azalea Caterpillar (Box 1, Folder 13)
  - Azalea Lace Bug (Box 1, Folder 14)
  - Azalea Leaf Miner (Box 1, Folder 15)
  - Azalea Stem Borer (Box 1, Folder 16)
  - Azalea Whitefly (Box 1, Folder 17)
  - Bagworms (Box 1, Folder 18)
  - Balsam Twig Aphid (Box 1, Folder 19)
  - Balsam Wooly Aphid (Box 1, Folder 20)
  - Banded Greenhouse / Sugarbeet Thrips (Box 1, Folder 21)
  - Banded Wingless Whitefly (Box 1, Folder 22)
  - Banks Grass Mite (Box 1, Folder 23)
  - Bark Lice (Box 1, Folder 24)
  - Bean Aphid (Box 1, Folder 25)
  - Bean Leaf Beetle (Box 1, Folder 26)
  - Bedbug (Box 2, Folder 1)
  - Beet Armyworm (Box 2, Folder 2)
  - Beneficials (Box 2, Folder 3)
  - Bermuda Grass Mite (Box 2, Folder 4)
  - Bill Bugs (Box 2, Folder 5)
  - Birch / Willow / Sycamore Aphids (Box 2, Folder 6)
  - Birds (Box 2, Folder 7)
  - Biting Midge (Box 2, Folder 8)
  - Black Cutworm (Box 2, Folder 9)
  - Black Fly (Buffalo Gnat) (Box 2, Folder 10)
  - Black Garbage Fly (Box 2, Folder 11)
  - Black Soldier Fly (Box 2, Folder 12)
  - Black Turpentine Beetle (Box 2, Folder 13)
  - Black Vine Weevil (Box 2, Folder 14)
  - Black Walnut Curculio (Box 2, Folder 15)
  - Blister Beetles (Box 2, Folder 16)
  - Blowflies (Box 2, Folder 17)
  - Blueberry Bud Mite (Box 2, Folder 18)
  - Blueberry Maggot (Box 2, Folder 19)
  - Boll Weevil (Box 3, Folder 1)
  - Bollworm (Box 3, Folder 2)
  - Boxelder Bug (Box 3, Folder 3)
  - Boxwood Leaf Miner (Box 3, Folder 4)
  - Boxwood Psyllid (Box 3, Folder 5)
  - Boxwood Spider Mite (Box 3, Folder 6)
  - Broad Mite (Box 3, Folder 7)
  - Bronzed Cutworm (Box 3, Folder 8)
  - Brown Garden Snail (Box 3, Folder 9)
  - Brown Soft Scale (Box 3, Folder 10)
  - Brown Stink Bug (Box 3, Folder 11)
  - Browntail Moth (Box 3, Folder 12)
  - Brown Wheat Mite (Box 3, Folder 13)
  - Bugs (Box 3, Folder 14)
  - Bulb Flies (Box 3, Folder 15)
  - Bulb Mite (Box 3, Folder 16)
  - Burrowing Sod Webworm (Box 3, Folder 17)
  - Butternut Curculio (Box 3, Folder 18)
  - Cabbage Aphid (Box 3, Folder 19)
  - Cabbage Looper (Box 3, Folder 20)
  - Cabbage Maggot (Box 3, Folder 21)
  - Cabbage Webworm (Box 3, Folder 22)
  - Cactus Scale (Box 3, Folder 23)
  - Cadella (Box 3, Folder 24)
  - Camel Cricket (Box 3, Folder 25)
  - Carpenter Worm (Box 3, Folder 26)
  - Carrot Beetle (Box 3, Folder 27)
  - Caterpillars (Box 3, Folder 28)
  - Cattle Biting Louse (Box 3, Folder 29)
  - Cecidomyiid (Box 3, Folder 30)
  - Cerambycid (Box 3, Folder 31)
  - Cereal Leaf Beetle (Box 3, Folder 32)
  - Chaff Scale (Box 3, Folder 33)
  - Cherry Fruit Flies (Box 3, Folder 34)
  - Chicken Body Louse (Box 4, Folder 1)
  - Chiggers (Box 4, Folder 2)
  - Chinch Bug (Box 4, Folder 3)
  - Choristoneura (Box 4, Folder 4)
  - Chrysanthemum Aphid (Box 4, Folder 5)
  - Chrysanthemum Lace Bug (Box 4, Folder 6)
  - Cicada / Cicada Killer (Box 4, Folder 7)
  - Cigarette Beetle (Box 4, Folder 8)
  - Cinara Aphids (Box 4, Folder 9)
  - Citrus Black Fly (Box 4, Folder 10)
  - Citrus Bud Mite (Box 4, Folder 11)
  - Citrus Red Mite (Box 4, Folder 12)
  - Citrus Rust Mite (Box 4, Folder 13)
  - Citrus Whitefly (Box 4, Folder 14)
  - Clearwinged Grasshopper (Box 4, Folder 15)
  - Clover Leafhopper (Box 4, Folder 16)
  - Clover Leaf Weevil (Box 4, Folder 17)
  - Clover Mite (Box 4, Folder 18)
  - Clover Root Curculio (Box 4, Folder 19)
  - Codling Moth (Box 4, Folder 20)
  - Cockroaches (Box 4, Folder 21)
  - Coelioxys (Box 4, Folder 22)
  - Coleoptera (Box 4, Folder 23)
  - Collembola (Box 4, Folder 24)
  - Colorado Potato Beetle (Box 4, Folder 25)
  - Coloring Books, Entomological (Box 4, Folder 26)
  - Common Cattle Grub (Box 4, Folder 27)
  - Confused Flour Beetle (Box 4, Folder 28)
  - Corn Earworm (Box 4, Folder 29)
  - Corn Flea Beetle (Box 4, Folder 30)
  - Corn Root Aphid (Box 4, Folder 31)
  - Corn Wireworm (Box 5, Folder 1)
  - Cotton Fleahopper (Box 5, Folder 2)
  - Cotton Leaf Perforator (Box 5, Folder 3)
  - Cotton Leaf Worm (Box 5, Folder 4)
  - Cottony Cushion Scale (Box 5, Folder 5)
  - Cottony Maple Scale (Box 5, Folder 6)
  - Cowpea Aphid (Box 5, Folder 7)
  - Cowpea Curculio (Box 5, Folder 8)
  - Crab Louse (Box 5, Folder 9)
  - Crane Fly (Box 5, Folder 10)
  - Crape Myrtle Aphid (Box 5, Folder 11)
  - Crescent-Marked Lily Aphid (Box 5, Folder 12)
  - Crickets (Box 5, Folder 13)
  - Cross-Striped Cabbage Worm (Box 5, Folder 14)
  - Cutworms (Box 5, Folder 15)
  - Cyclamen Mite (Box 5, Folder 16)
  - Dectes Stem Borer (Box 5, Folder 17)
  - Deer Flies (Box 5, Folder 18)
  - Diamondback Moth (Box 5, Folder 19)
  - Diptera (Box 5, Folder 20)
  - Dobsonfly (Box 5, Folder 21)
  - Dogwood Borer (Box 5, Folder 22)
  - Dogwood Club Gall Midge (Box 5, Folder 23)
  - Dogwood Twig Borer (Box 5, Folder 24)
  - Drone Fly (Box 5, Folder 25)
  - Dump Fly (Box 5, Folder 26)
  - Dusky Birch Sawfly (Box 5, Folder 27)
  - Dusky Sap Beetle (Box 5, Folder 28)
  - Earwig (Box 5, Folder 29)
  - Earthworm (Box 5, Folder 30)
  - Eastern Field Wireworm (Box 5, Folder 31)
  - Eastern Spruce Gall Adelgid (Box 6, Folder 1)
  - Eggplant Flea Beetle (Box 6, Folder 2)
  - Eggplant Lace Bug (Box 6, Folder 3)
  - Elodes (Tenebrionidae) (Box 6, Folder 4)
  - Elm Bark Beetle (Box 6, Folder 5)
  - Elm Leaf Beetle (Box 6, Folder 6)
  - English Grain Aphid (Box 6, Folder 7)
  - Episimus (Box 6, Folder 8)
  - Eriophyid / Birch Willow Mite (Box 6, Folder 9)
  - Eulachnus (Box 6, Folder 10)
  - Euonymus Scale (Box 6, Folder 11)
  - European Chafer (Box 6, Folder 12)
  - European Corn Borer (Box 6, Folder 13)
  - European Earwig (Box 6, Folder 14)
  - European Pine Shoot Moth (Box 6, Folder 15)
  - European Red Mite (Box 6, Folder 16)
  - Eye Gnats (Box 6, Folder 17)
  - Face Fly (Box 6, Folder 18)
  - Fall Armyworm (Box 6, Folder 19)
  - Fall Cankerworm (Box 6, Folder 20)
  - Fall Webworm (Box 6, Folder 21)
  - False Spider Mites (Box 6, Folder 22)
  - False Stable Fly (Box 6, Folder 23)
  - Fern Scale (Box 6, Folder 24)
  - Flatheaded Appletree Borer (Box 6, Folder 25)
  - Fleas (Box 6, Folder 26)
  - Flea Beetle (Box 6, Folder 27)
  - Flesh Fly (Box 6, Folder 28)
  - Florida Fern Caterpillar (Box 6, Folder 29)
  - Florida Red Scale (Box 7, Folder 1)
  - Foxglove (Box 7, Folder 2)
  - Fruit Fly (Box 7, Folder 3)
  - Fuller Rose Beetle (Box 7, Folder 4)
  - Fungus Gnat (Box 7, Folder 5)
  - Galls (Cynipids) (Box 7, Folder 6)
  - Gall Mites (Box 7, Folder 7)
  - Garden Fleahopper (Box 7, Folder 8)
  - Geranium Aphid (Box 7, Folder 9)
  - Geranium Plume Moth (Box 7, Folder 10)
  - Giant African Snail (Box 7, Folder 11)
  - Giant Bark Aphid (Box 7, Folder 12)
  - Gladiolus Thrip (Box 7, Folder 13)
  - Gloomy Scale (Box 7, Folder 14)
  - Glover Scale (Box 7, Folder 15)
  - Granulate Cutworm (Box 7, Folder 16)
  - Grape Berry Moth (Box 7, Folder 17)
  - Grape Colaspis (Box 7, Folder 18)
  - Grape Flea Beetle (Box 7, Folder 19)
  - Grape Leaf Folder (Box 7, Folder 20)
  - Grape Phylloxera (Box 7, Folder 21)
  - Grape Root Borer (Box 7, Folder 22)
  - Grasshoppers (Box 7, Folder 23)
  - Greedy Scale (Box 7, Folder 24)
  - Greenbug (Box 7, Folder 25)
  - Green Cloverworm (Box 7, Folder 26)
  - Greenhouses (Box 7, Folder 27)
  - Greenhouse Leaftier (Box 7, Folder 28)
  - Greenhouse Thrips (Box 7, Folder 29)
  - Greenhouse Whitefly (Box 7, Folder 30)
  - Green June Beetle (Box 7, Folder 31)
  - Green Peach Aphid (Box 8, Folder 1)
  - Green Stink Bug (Box 8, Folder 2)
  - Greenstriped Mapleworm (Box 8, Folder 3)
  - Ground Beetle (Box 8, Folder 4)
  - Ground Pearl (Box 8, Folder 5)
  - Gypsy Moth (Box 8, Folder 6)
  - Hackberry Leaf Slug (Box 8, Folder 7)
  - Harlequin Bug (Box 8, Folder 8)
  - Hawthorn Lace Bug (Box 8, Folder 9)
  - Head and Body Louse (Box 8, Folder 10)
  - Hemiptera (Box 8, Folder 11)
  - Hemispherical Scale (Box 8, Folder 12)
  - Hemlock Looper (Box 8, Folder 13)
  - Hemlock Rust Mite (Box 8, Folder 14)
  - Hessian Fly (Box 8, Folder 15)
  - Hickory Gall Aphid (Box 8, Folder 16)
  - Hickory Horned Devil (Box 8, Folder 17)
  - Hickory Shuckworm (Box 8, Folder 18)
  - Hog Louse (Box 8, Folder 19)
  - Holly Leaf Miner (Box 8, Folder 20)
  - Homoptera (Box 8, Folder 21)
  - Hornets (Box 8, Folder 22)
  - Horn Fly (Box 8, Folder 23)
  - Horse Botfly (Box 8, Folder 24)
  - Horsefly (Box 8, Folder 25)
  - Housefly (Box 8, Folder 26)
  - Hunting Billbug (Box 8, Folder 27)
  - Hymenoptera (illustrations and text) (Box 9, Folder 1)
  - Hymenoptera (prints and transparencies) (Box 9, Folder 2)
  - Hymenoptera (mounted illustrations) (Box 9, Folder 3)
  - Imported Cabbageworm (Box 9, Folder 4)
  - Imported Willow Leaf Beetle (Box 9, Folder 5)
  - Indian Meal Moth (Box 9, Folder 6)
  - Indian Wax Scale (Box 9, Folder 7)
  - Introduced Pine Sawfly (Box 9, Folder 8)
  - Ips Beetle (Box 9, Folder 9)
  - Iris Borer (Box 9, Folder 10)
  - Itch Mite (Box 9, Folder 11)
  - Japanese Beetle (Box 9, Folder 12)
  - Juniper Webworm (Box 9, Folder 13)
  - Key (1) (Box 9, Folder 14)
  - Key (2) (Box 9, Folder 15)
  - Lace Bugs (Box 9, Folder 16)
  - Lacewings (Box 9, Folder 17)
  - Ladybugs (Box 9, Folder 18)
  - Larger Elm Leaf Beetles (Box 9, Folder 19)
  - Leaf Beetles (Box 9, Folder 20)
  - Leaf Crumpler (Box 9, Folder 21)
  - Leaffooted Bug (Box 9, Folder 22)
  - Leafhoppers (1) (Box 9, Folder 23)
  - Leafhoppers (2) (Box 10, Folder 1)
  - Leaf Miners (Box 10, Folder 2)
  - Lecanium Scales (Box 10, Folder 3)
  - Lepidoptera (text) (Box 10, Folder 4)
  - Lepidoptera (illustrations) (Box 10, Folder 5)
  - Lepidoptera (photographs) (Box 10, Folder 6)
  - Lesser Canna Leafroller (Box 10, Folder 7)
  - Lesser Cornstalk Borer (Box 10, Folder 8)
  - Lesser Grain Borer (Box 10, Folder 9)
  - Lesser Housefly (Box 10, Folder 10)
  - Lesser Mealworm (Box 10, Folder 11)
  - Lesser Snow Scale (Box 10, Folder 12)
  - Ligustrum Weevil (Box 10, Folder 13)
  - Lilac Borer (Box 10, Folder 14)
  - Lima Bean Vine Borer (Box 10, Folder 15)
  - Liriomyza Trifolii (Box 10, Folder 16)
  - Livestock (Box 10, Folder 17)
  - Locust Borer (Box 10, Folder 18)
  - Locust Leaf Miner (Box 10, Folder 19)
  - Locust Twig Borer (Box 10, Folder 20)
  - Loxostege Webworm (Box 10, Folder 21)
  - Lygus Bug (Box 10, Folder 22)
  - Lysiphlebus Wasp (Stinging Aphid) (Box 11, Folder 1)
  - Magnolia Scale (Box 11, Folder 2)
  - Mammals (Box 11, Folder 3)
  - Maple Bladder Gall (Box 11, Folder 4)
  - Maple Eyespot Gall (Box 11, Folder 5)
  - March Fly (Box 11, Folder 6)
  - May Beetle (White Grub) (Box 11, Folder 7)
  - Mediterranean Fruit Fly (Box 11, Folder 8)
  - Mealybugs (Box 11, Folder 9)
  - Meadow Spittlebug (Box 11, Folder 10)
  - Megaloptera (Box 11, Folder 11)
  - Melon Aphid (Box 11, Folder 12)
  - Mexican Bean Beetle (Box 11, Folder 13)
  - Mexican Fruit Fly (Box 11, Folder 14)
  - Millipede / Centipede (Box 11, Folder 15)
  - Mimosa Webworm (Box 11, Folder 16)
  - Miscellaneous (Box 11, Folder 17)
  - Mites (Box 11, Folder 18)
  - Mole Cricket (Box 11, Folder 19)
  - Monochamus (Box 11, Folder 20)
  - Mosquitos (Box 11, Folder 21)
  - Morning Cloak Butterfly (Box 11, Folder 22)
  - Nantucket Pine Tip Moth (Box 11, Folder 23)
  - Nematodes (Roundworms) (Box 12, Folder 1)
  - Northern Corn Rootworm (Box 12, Folder 2)
  - Northern Fowl Mite (Box 12, Folder 3)
  - Neuroptera (Box 12, Folder 4)
  - Oak Leaf Miner (Box 12, Folder 5)
  - One-Page Handouts (originals) (Box 12, Folder 6)
  - One-Page Handouts (duplicates) (Box 12, Folder 7)
  - Onion Thrips (Box 12, Folder 8)
  - Orange-Striped Oakworm (Box 12, Folder 9)
  - Oystershell Scale (Box 12, Folder 10)
  - Palestriped Flea Beetle (Box 12, Folder 11)
  - Pale Western Cutworm (Box 12, Folder 12)
  - Pales Weevil (Box 12, Folder 13)
  - Parsleyworm (Box 12, Folder 14)
  - Pea Aphid (Box 12, Folder 15)
  - Peachtree Borer (Box 12, Folder 16)
  - Pecan Leaf Casebearer (Box 12, Folder 17)
  - Pecan Nut Casebearer (Box 12, Folder 18)
  - Pecan Shuckworm (Box 12, Folder 19)
  - Pecan Weevil (Box 12, Folder 20)
  - Peony Scale (Box 12, Folder 21)
  - Pepper Maggot (Box 12, Folder 22)
  - Pepper Weevil (Box 12, Folder 23)
  - Persimmon Borer (Box 12, Folder 24)
  - Phylloxeridae (Box 12, Folder 25)
  - Pickleworm / Melonworm (Box 12, Folder 26)
  - Pillbugs / Sowbugs (Box 12, Folder 27)
  - Pine Bark Adelgid (Box 12, Folder 28)
  - Pine Needle Scale (Box 12, Folder 29)
  - Pine Spittlebug (Box 12, Folder 30)
  - Pine Tortoise Scale (Box 12, Folder 31)
  - Plant Bugs (Box 12, Folder 32)
  - Planthoppers (Box 12, Folder 33)
  - Platynota (Leafroller) (Box 12, Folder 34)
  - Plum Curculio (Box 13, Folder 1)
  - Plume Moth (Box 13, Folder 2)
  - Poplar Tentmaker (Box 13, Folder 3)
  - Potato Aphid (Box 13, Folder 4)
  - Potato Flea Beetle (Box 13, Folder 5)
  - Potato Leafhopper (Box 13, Folder 6)
  - Potato Tuberworm (Box 13, Folder 7)
  - Poultry Mites (Box 13, Folder 8)
  - Praying Mantis (Box 13, Folder 9)
  - Privet Rust Mite (Box 13, Folder 10)
  - Purple Scale (Box 13, Folder 11)
  - Redbanded Leafroller (Box 13, Folder 12)
  - Redbud Leafroller (Box 13, Folder 13)
  - Redheaded Pine Sawfly (Box 13, Folder 14)
  - Redhumped Caterpillar (Box 13, Folder 15)
  - Red Scale (Box 13, Folder 16)
  - Rhabdopterous Beetle (Box 13, Folder 17)
  - Rhodesgrass Scale (Box 13, Folder 18)
  - Rhododendron Borer (Box 13, Folder 19)
  - Rhododendron Lace Bug (Box 13, Folder 20)
  - Rhododendron Tip Midge (Box 13, Folder 21)
  - Rice Weevil (Box 13, Folder 22)
  - Rodents (Box 13, Folder 23)
  - Rose Aphid (Box 13, Folder 24)
  - Rose Chafer (Box 13, Folder 25)
  - Rose Midge (Box 13, Folder 26)
  - Roundheaded Appletree Borer (Box 13, Folder 27)
  - Salt-Marsh Caterpillar (Box 13, Folder 28)
  - Salt-Marsh Mosquito (Box 13, Folder 29)
  - San Jose Scale (Box 13, Folder 30)
  - Sand Flies (Box 13, Folder 31)
  - Sawtoothed Grain Beetle (Box 13, Folder 32)
  - Scab Mite (Box 13, Folder 33)
  - Scale (conversion, to metric) (Box 13, Folder 34)
  - Scarab Beetle (Box 13, Folder 35)
  - Scoliidae (Box 13, Folder 36)
  - Seedcorn Maggot (Box 13, Folder 37)
  - Serpentine Leaf Miner (Box 13, Folder 38)
  - Sheep Botfly (Box 13, Folder 39)
  - Sheep Ked (Box 13, Folder 40)
  - Shoreflies (Box 13, Folder 41)
  - Slugs and Snails (Box 13, Folder 42)
  - Sod Webworm (Box 13, Folder 43)
  - Soldier Beetle (Box 13, Folder 44)
  - Solitary Oak Leaf Miner (Box 14, Folder 1)
  - Sorghum Midge (Box 14, Folder 2)
  - Sorghum Webworm (Box 14, Folder 3)
  - Southern Armyworm (Box 14, Folder 4)
  - Southern Corn Rootworm (Box 14, Folder 5)
  - Southern Cornstalk Borer (Box 14, Folder 6)
  - Southern Pine Beetle (Box 14, Folder 7)
  - Southern Red Mite (Box 14, Folder 8)
  - Southwestern Corn Borer (Box 14, Folder 9)
  - Soybean Looper (Box 14, Folder 10)
  - Spider Mites (Box 14, Folder 11)
  - Spiders (Box 14, Folder 12)
  - Spittlebugs (Box 14, Folder 13)
  - Spinach Flea Beetle (Box 14, Folder 14)
  - Spring Rose Beetle (Box 14, Folder 15)
  - Spruce Spider Mite (Box 14, Folder 16)
  - Squash Bug (Box 14, Folder 17)
  - Squash Vine Borer (Box 14, Folder 18)
  - Stable Fly (Box 14, Folder 19)
  - Stalk Borers (Box 14, Folder 20)
  - Stilt Bug (Box 14, Folder 21)
  - Stinging Caterpillars (Box 14, Folder 22)
  - Stink Bugs (Box 14, Folder 23)
  - Strawberry Crown Borer (Box 14, Folder 24)
  - Strawberry Root Aphid (Box 14, Folder 25)
  - Strawberry Root Weevil (Box 14, Folder 26)
  - Striped Cucumber Beetle (Box 14, Folder 27)
  - Striped Flea Beetle (Box 14, Folder 28)
  - Striped Ground Cricket (Box 14, Folder 29)
  - Studies, Graduate (NCSU Entomology Department) (Box 14, Folder 30)
  - Suckfly (Box 14, Folder 31)
  - Sugarcane Beetle (Box 15, Folder 1)
  - Sugarcane Borer (Box 15, Folder 2)
  - Sugarcane Rootstock Borer Weevil (Box 15, Folder 3)
  - Sweet Potato Hornworm (Box 15, Folder 4)
  - Sweet Potato Weevil (Box 15, Folder 5)
  - Sweet Potato Whitefly (Box 15, Folder 6)
  - Sycamore Casebearing Beetle (Box 15, Folder 7)
  - Sycamore Lace Bug (Box 15, Folder 8)
  - Syrphid Fly (Box 15, Folder 9)
  - Tea Scale (Box 15, Folder 10)
  - Telenomus (Box 15, Folder 11)
  - Tent Caterpillars (Box 15, Folder 12)
  - Termites (Box 15, Folder 13)
  - Threecornered Alfalfa Hopper (Box 15, Folder 14)
  - Thrips (small prints and transparencies) (Box 15, Folder 15)
  - Thrips (large prints and transparencies) (Box 15, Folder 16)
  - Thrips (illustrations) (Box 15, Folder 17)
  - Ticks (Box 15, Folder 18)
  - Tiger Beetles (Box 15, Folder 19)
  - Tobacco Budworm (Box 15, Folder 20)
  - Tobacco Flea Beetle (Box 15, Folder 21)
  - Tobacco Hornworm (Box 15, Folder 22)
  - Tobacco Moth (Box 15, Folder 23)
  - Tobacco Thrip (Box 15, Folder 24)
  - Tomato Hornworm (Box 15, Folder 25)
  - Tomato Pinworm (Box 16, Folder 1)
  - Tortoise Beetles (Box 16, Folder 2)
  - Tufted Apple Budworm (Box 16, Folder 3)
  - Tulip Bulb Aphid (Box 16, Folder 4)
  - Turnip Aphid (Box 16, Folder 5)
  - Tussock Moth (Box 16, Folder 6)
  - Twig Girdler (Box 16, Folder 7)
  - Twobanded Japanese Weevil (Box 16, Folder 8)
  - Two-Spotted Spidermite (Box 16, Folder 9)
  - Variegated Cutworm (Box 16, Folder 10)
  - Vegetable Weevil (Box 16, Folder 11)
  - Velvet Ant (Cow Killer) (Box 16, Folder 12)
  - Velvetbean Caterpillar (Box 16, Folder 13)
  - Vinegar Fly (Box 16, Folder 14)
  - Walnut Caterpillar (Box 16, Folder 15)
  - Walnut Husk Fly (Box 16, Folder 16)
  - Wasps (Box 16, Folder 17)
  - Western Corn Rootworm (Box 16, Folder 18)
  - Western Flower Thrips (text and illustrations) (Box 16, Folder 19)
  - Western Flower Thrips (photographs and mounted illustrations) (Box 16, Folder 20)
  - Wheat Stem Maggot (Box 16, Folder 21)
  - Wheat Stem Sawfly (Box 16, Folder 22)
  - Wheat Wireworm (Box 16, Folder 23)
  - Wheel Bug (Box 16, Folder 24)
  - Whitefly (Box 16, Folder 25)
  - Whitefringed Beetle (Box 17, Folder 1)